《サスケ：俺は…　どれぐらい強い？》
How strong am I?
You are weak!
((我愛羅：お前は弱い。
You are naïve.
お前は甘い。
Shut up...
黙れ…。
Because your hatred is weak.
憎しみが弱いからだ。
黙れ！
Shut up!
（我愛羅）憎しみの力は殺意の力。
The power of hatred is
the power to kill!
殺意の力は復讐の力…
お前の憎しみは　俺より弱い！
The power to kill is
the power of revenge!
Your hatred is weaker than mine!
黙れ！
Enough!
♪～
（サクラ）サスケ君！
Sasuke!
Damn it!
(（ナルト）クソ！))
((ナルト　サクラ！
お前たちは逃げろ！
Naruto, Sakura...
You two get out of here!
((俺は一度　すべてを失った。
I lost everything once...
もう　俺の目の前で→
I don't want to see the friends I cherish
die right before my eyes.
(大切な仲間が死ぬのは
見たくない！))
♪～
I was helpless.
《俺は…　何もできなかった》
((う！　ず！　ま！　き！
Na-Ru-To!
(ナルト　二千連弾の巻！))
2K Uzumaki...
Barrage!
♪～
Naruto keeps growing
unbelievably strong.
《ナルトは　異常なまでに
どんどん強くなっていく。
近くで見ているとわかる。
何か　すごい力を秘めている。
I can tell just by watching him.
He has some kind of
enormous power inside him...
ときどき…
恐怖すら感じるほどに》
And once in a while,
it even makes me scared.
How...?
俺は…
俺は　どうしたら強くなれる！？
How can I become strong?
どうしたら…　復讐を果たせる！？
How can I get my revenge?
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
10th Anniversary 4-Episode Special
Rift
He's returned to the village?!
《アイツが
この里へ帰ってきただと！？
But he's after Naruto?
しかも　ナルトを追っている。
どういうことだ！？
What's going on?!
クソ！》
Damn it!
It's been a long time, Sasuke.
（イタチ）久しぶりだな　サスケ。
Huh?
え？
Itachi Uchiha...
うちはイタチ…　アンタを…。
I will...
kill you!
殺す！
Oh... the Sharingan.
（鬼鮫）ほう…　写輪眼。
いったい　何者です？
Just who is he?
My little brother.
（イタチ）俺の弟だ。
（鬼鮫）うちは一族は
皆殺しにされたと聞きましたが…。
I had heard that the Uchiha Clan
had been annihilated... by you.
あなたに。
《コイツが…　サスケの言ってた
殺したい男！》
So this is the man
Sasuke was talking about...
The one he wants to kill!
((イタチ：貴様など　殺す価値もない。
There is no value in killing you now,
my foolish little brother.
愚かなる弟よ…
この俺を殺したくば→
If you wish to kill me,
resent me, hate me,
恨め　憎め…
そして　醜く生き延びるがいい。
and survive in obscurity.
Run... Keep running and cling to life.
(逃げて　逃げて…
生にしがみつくがいい))
アンタの言ったとおり
アンタを恨み　憎み→
It's just as you've said.
I've hated you and resented you.
そして　アンタを殺すためだけに
俺は！
For the singular purpose
of killing you...
I have lived my life!
俺は…　生きてきた！
うおぉ～っ！
ぐあ～っ！
Sasuke!
サスケ！！　チクショウ…。
Damn it!
その腕を斬り落としましょうか！
Maybe I should cut off those arms!
（イタチ）自来也様…。
Master Jiraiya...
（自来也）目当ては　やはり　ナルトか？
So your target is Naruto, after all?
（イタチ）ナルト君を連れてゆくのが→
To take Naruto is the overriding mission
we have been assigned by the Akatsuki.
暁から下された
我々への至上命令。
（自来也）ナルトは…　やれんのう。
I can't let you have Naruto.
どうですかね。
I wonder about that...
Perfect timing. I will get rid of
both of you right here.
ちょうどいい。　お前ら２人は
ここで　わしが始末する。
手　出すな…。
Don't interfere.
If anyone is going to kill him,
コイツを…　殺すのは…。
俺だ。
it will be me.
今　お前などに興味はない。
I have no interest in you right now.
Sasuke!
サスケ！
Damn it!
チクショウが…。
ナルト！
手　出すなっつってんだろうが！！
Naruto!
I said not to interfere!
これは　俺の戦いだ。
This is my fight!
《復讐か》
Revenge...
上等だ！
Fine!
《なんで…　あのときから
少しも縮まらない…。
Why? I haven't closed the gap at all.
この差は　何だ？》
What is this difference?
ぐあっ…。
《コイツを殺すため
俺は　ずっと修業を…。
I've trained for so long,
just to kill him.
ずっと…》
For so long!
《今まで俺は
何をしていたんだ…》
What have I been doing
all this time?!
《いったい　俺は…》
Just what...?
((イタチ：お前は弱い。
You are weak.
(今から２４時間　あの日をさまよえ))
From now, for 24 hours...
Go back to that day.
いいかげんに…　しやがれ！！
That's enough...
outta you!
忍法　蝦蟇口縛り。
Ninja Art: Toad Mouth Trap.
残念だのう　イタチ　鬼鮫。
Too bad, Itachi... Kisame.
お前らは　もう　わしの腹の中。
You are in my belly now!
妙木山　岩宿の
大蝦蟇の食堂を口寄せした。
I've summoned the digestive tract
of the Giant Toad of Mount Myoboku.
お前らは　どうせお尋ね者だ。
You are wanted criminals anyway.
このまま
岩蝦蟇のエサにしてやるからのう。
I'll just feed you to the rock toad.
You are weak
because you don't have enough...
なぜ弱いか…　足りないからだ。
憎しみが。
hatred.
鬼鮫　来い。
チッ。
Come, Kisame!
Damn!
待てって！
Wait!
この野郎！
Why you—!
これまで　この術から
抜け出せたヤツはおらんのう。
No one's ever escaped
this jutsu before!
うむ…。
どうしたんだってばよ！
What's the matter, hey?!
いないってばよ…。
They're gone!
サスケ。
Sasuke!
サスケ…　しっかりしろ　サスケ。
Are you all right, Sasuke?!
サスケ！　チクショウ　何だってばよ。
Sasuke!
Damn it!
What's going on?
アイツ　サスケに何しやがったんだ！
What did that guy do to him?!
イタチの写輪眼だ。
It's Itachi's Sharingan.
何やら　瞳術で
精心攻撃を食らっておる。
He used his visual prowess to
weaken his will to attack.
相当なダメージを受けとるようだのう。
He's hurt quite badly.
サスケ。
わしと同じ　三忍の１人。
Sasuke...
I guess we'll just have to find her.
病払いのナメクジ使い
綱手を見つけてくるしかなかろう。
Tsunade, the Queen
of Slugs and Elixirs,
who's a Sannin like me.
《待ってろよ　サスケ。
Hang in there, Sasuke.
お前を治せる綱手って人→
I swear I'll find this Tsunade
who can heal you.
絶対見つけてくっからよ！》
どうした？
エロ仙人。
What is it?
Pervy Sage,
why did they come after me?
アイツら　何で俺を狙ってきたのかな。
うん…　ヤツらが狙っているのは→
It's not you they're after,
but what's inside of you.
お前というより
お前のなかのものだ。
いったいコイツってば
何なんだってばよ。
Just what is this thing anyway?
コイツってば
木ノ葉を襲ったバケモンだろ。
This thing's a monster that attacked
Hidden Leaf Village, right?
だから
みんなに恐れられてるのに→
That's why everyone's so scared.
何でアイツらは
ほしがってんだってばよ。
So why would they want
something like that?
確かに　九尾は　昔から
時代時代の節目に現れ→
It's a fact the Nine Tails
has appeared, and caused havoc,
あらゆるものを
破壊し尽くしてきた妖魔。
generation after generation
at critical points in history.
だから昔の人々は天災の
ひとつとして九尾を恐れた。
That's why people have feared
this apparition as a natural disaster.
お前の中に
九尾が封印されている以上→
Perhaps they feel that
if you have the Nine Tails
sealed inside you,
ヤツらは　その力を
自分たちの支配下に置きたいと→
they want to have its power
under their control.
考えているのかもしれん。
あんなヤツらに狙われ続けるのは
酷な話だがのう。
It's a nuisance to have them
coming after you relentlessly.
これも定め。
まぁわしがお前を守ってやるから。
But that's your fate.
And I am here to protect you.
Then...
だったら…　だったら
さっさと強くなんなきゃな。
Then I'd better not waste time
and get strong quickly!
俺ってばよ。
Where am I?
ここは…。
（綱手）よし。
Good, you're out of the woods.
もう大丈夫だ。
俺は…。
I...?
Sasuke!
（サクラ）サスケ君！
サスケ　お前…。
Sasuke you...!
You're pretty thoughtful, aren't you?
案外　気が利くんだな。
I didn't do anything!
そんなんじゃねえってばよ。
いい仲間だな。
You're a good friend.
エヘヘッ。
You are weak...
((なぜ弱いか。　足りないからだ。
because you don't have enough...
(憎しみが))
hatred.
Sasuke, have some apples.
サスケ君　リンゴよ。
Sasuke?
サスケ君？
W-What is it?
な…　なんだよ。
Naruto, fight me now.
ナルト…　今から俺と戦え！
Huh?! What're you saying?
You're not even completely healed!
えっ？　病み上がりのくせに
何言ってんだ？
I don't care. Just fight me!
いいから戦え！
And you think you're helping me?
俺を助けたつもりか？
The Fifth Hokage or whatever...
五代目だか何だか知らねえが→
She should've minded
her own business!
余計なことしやがって！
What?!
なに！？
Sasuke, what's wrong?
サ…　サスケ君
ちょっと　どうしちゃったの？
Naruto, do something...
ナルトも　なんとか…。
Sure, this is perfect.
ちょうどいいってばよ。
I've wanted to fight you.
俺も　お前と戦いたいと思ってた。
What is this I'm feeling?
《何だ？　この気持…。
I feel tightness in my gut...
下っ腹のあたりがキュンとする。
and something thrilling...
それに…　ゾクゾクする！》
ヘッ！
What's so funny?
何がおかしい？
I'm not laughing. I'm happy...
おかしいんじゃねえってばよ。
嬉しいんだよ！
Just thinking about how
I'm gonna get to beat you.
お前に　ここで
やっと勝てると思ったらな！
What?
何だと！？
To take Naruto is
the overriding mission
((ナルト君を連れて行くのが→
we have been assigned
by the Akatsuki.
(暁から下された
我々への至上命令))
Losers shouldn't ramble.
落ちこぼれが　ほざいてんなよ。
I'm not a loser that gets in
everyone's way anymore.
いつまでも落ちこぼれの
足手まといじゃねえぜ。
I have no interest
in you right now.
((今　お前などに興味はない))
Why you loser!
テメエ　このウスラトンカチが！
なに図にのってんだ！
Don't act so high and mighty!
ヘッ！　クールなお前が
いつになく喚くな。
Aren't you supposed to be cool?
Quit making such a fuss.
らしくねぇじゃねえの。
Or maybe, you're a little scared
and regret challenging me, Sasuke?
もしかしてケンカ売っといて
ビビッてんじゃねえのか？　サスケ！
Come on!
さっさとこい！
Before that, put your headband on.
その前に額当てをしろ。
いらねえよ　そんなもんは。
I don't need that thing.
Just do it!
いいからしろ！
I'm saying this is a testament
これは　木ノ葉の忍として→
to fighting on equal terms
as Leaf Ninja.
対等に戦う
証しだって言ってんだよ。
That's exactly why I'm saying
you're acting high and mighty!
そういうのが図にのってるって
いうんだ！
No, he's already...
《違う　アイツはもう…》
Do you really think
that we're equals?
テメエと俺が　対等だとでも
思ってんのか！？
Can I keep up with him?
《俺は
アイツと対等でいられるのか？》
Yeah, I do!
ああ！　思ってる！
No, I don't.
《思ってねえ…》
I've never once thought that
I was inferior to you!
俺は一度も　お前に
劣ってると思ったことはねえ！
You're what I strive to be!
《お前は　俺の憧れだったんだ》
You're an embarrassment!
目障りなんだよ！
I have to stop!
《やめろ！》
That's because
you're still weak, Little Sasuke!
それは　お前が
弱いままだからだろうが！
サスケちゃんよ！
I have to stop!
《やめろ！》
Naruto!
ナルト！
サスケ！
Sasuke!
Stop it!
やめて！
You jerk!
クソが！
うお～！
２人とも　やめて～！
Stop it, you two!
Damn!
《クソッ！》
《止めきれねえ！》
I can't stop completely!
（２人）うおっ！
What are you guys doing
up on the roof of the hospital?
（カカシ）病院の上で何やってんの？
You two went a bit too far
just for a fight.
ケンカにしちゃ　ちょい
やりすぎでしょうよ　キミたち。
くっ…。
うっ…。
Sasuke, why are you standing
there gloating?
（カカシ）サスケ
なに優越感なんかに浸ってる。
さっきの千鳥　同じ里の仲間に
向ける大きさじゃなかったが…。
The size of that Chidori
was not the size
you would aim at a comrade
from the Leaf Village.
Did you intend to kill Naruto, Sasuke?
ナルトを殺す気だったのか？
フン。
That hole! What happened?!
《なんだ？　あの穴は！
どうなってる！？》
Naruto, how far will you go?
《ナルト！
お前は　いったい　どこまで…》
Was it you who taught him
that technique?
あなたですか？
あの術を教えたのは。
例の暁への対抗手段だとしても
螺旋丸を　ナルトに教えるなんて…。
Even if it were a means
to resist the Akatsuki,
to think that you would
teach Naruto the Rasengan.
If he slipped up,
he would have killed Sasuke.
下手したら　サスケを殺していた。
Right back at you...
お互いさまだろのう。
That Chidori was also
considerably risky.
あの千鳥も
相当　やばかったしのう。
But I didn't think
Naruto was the kind of kid
でも　まぁ　ナルトは　あの術を→
who'd fire that jutsu
at his comrade.
仲間に向けて撃つようなヤツじゃ
ないと思ってたんだがのう。
To Naruto, Sasuke is a comrade
and a rival at the same time.
ナルトにとって　サスケは
仲間であると同時に　ライバル。
Well, someone he considers an equal.
まぁ　常に対等な存在でありたい男
ってことです。
Most likely, he couldn't take
Sasuke's cheap provocations.
おそらく　そのサスケの安い挑発に
耐え切れなかったんでしょう。
He's been chasing him
since the Academy days.
アカデミーの頃から　ずっと
追っかけてきましたからね。
For him, it's neither
you nor me now.
今のナルトは　私やあなたじゃなく→
More than anyone,
he wants to be recognized by Sasuke.
誰よりも
ただ　認めてもらいたいんですよ。
サスケにね。
On the other side of the coin,
一方で　サスケは
ナルトの成長スピードを身近で感じて→
Sasuke feels the speed of
Naruto's growth at close range
and feels inferior.
劣等感を抱いている。
Naruto has gotten strong.
自分が　まるで成長していない
と　思いこんでしまうほどに→
To the extent that he thinks
he isn't growing at all.
ナルトは強くなりましたから。
Revenge, huh?
（自来也）復讐か…。　イタチのヤツが
あの子を焦らせてるのかのう？
I wonder if Itachi is
the one frustrating him.
That's why Sasuke doesn't
want to acknowledge Naruto.
（カカシ）だから　サスケは
ナルトを認めたくない。
If he acknowledges him,
認めてしまえば　今までの自分を
否定してしまいかねない。
he might deny himself
up to this point...
Rivalry is a difficult thing.
難しいもんです　ライバルってのはね。
On top of which, they are both
burdened by a dark past.
（自来也）おまけに　２人ともが
おのれの内に闇を抱えておる。
One that neither had control over.
それも
本人の意志とは関係なくな。
Damn it...
《チクショウ…。
Damn it!
チクショウ！》
We're the Sound Ninja Four.
（鬼童丸）我ら　音の四人衆。
大蛇丸様の使いで来た。
We're here on orders
from Lord Orochimaru.
I'm in a bad mood right now.
俺は　今　機嫌が悪いんだ。
やるってんなら　手加減しねえぜ。
If you want to fight, just know
that I won't go easy on you.
You stop your babbling, weakling.
（左近）テメエ　弱ぇくせに
ピーコラ言ってんじゃねえぞ。
He called me... weak?
《弱いだと！？》
Hey, come over here.
ほら　来いよ。
I'm going to play do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do
on your ribs until they crack.
アバラ　ボッキボキで
ドレミファソラシド　奏でてやっから。
Are you saying that Orochimaru
left a Curse Mark on Sasuke's body?
サスケの体に　大蛇丸が
呪印を残していったってのかよ？
Yes.
うん…　サスケ君は　必ず　私を求める。
力を求めて　って…。
He said, "Sasuke will come to me
without fail, in search of power."
I see. I didn't know such
a thing happened.
そっか。　そんなことがあったのか。
大蛇丸…。
Orochimaru... I ran into him again
a little while back.
俺も　こないだ
また　会ったってばよ。
What?!
えっ！？
He was one of the Sannin
元三忍とかで　やたら強ぇし
危ねぇヤツだってばよ。
and he's ridiculously strong
and dangerous.
But, everything will be okay!
けど　大丈夫だ！
Sasuke wouldn't fall for
that guy's enticement.
サスケは　あんなヤツの誘いになんか
のらねえし→
He's already really powerful,
そんなこと　しなくっても
すっげぇ強ぇヤツだってばよ！
so he doesn't need to do
that kind of thing!
俺が保証する。
I guarantee it!
うぉ～！
Come with us.
（多由也）うちらと一緒に来い。
If you do,
Lord Orochimaru will give you power.
そうすれば
大蛇丸様が力をくれる。
お前の目的は　なんだ？
What is your goal?
Are you and your comrades
just going to comfort each other
この生ぬるい里で
仲間と傷のなめ合いでもして→
in a mundane village like this and
try to forget all about Itachi Uchiha?
忘れて暮らすのか？
うちはイタチのことを…。
Don't forget your goal.
目的を忘れるな。　この里は
お前にとって枷にしかならねえ。
A village like this does nothing
more than shackle you!
くだらねえ　つながりも
プチンとすりゃ　いいんだよ。
Just cut your stupid bond
with this place.
If you do that, you'll be able
to obtain amazing power.
そうすりゃ　お前は　もっと
すばらしい力を得ることができる。
Don't forget your goal.
（左近）目的を忘れるな。
My goal is to kill Itachi!
《俺の目的は　イタチを殺すこと！
必要なのは　力…》
For that, I need power!
you and I held hands tightly and a light was born
kimi to boku nigirishimeta futatsu no te no naka de
let's release it now
umareta hikari ima hanatou
the town, tinged amber by the sunset
kohaku iro no yuuyake ni somerareta
projects a sad light and shadow
machi wa kanashii hikari to kage utsushite ita
I've encountered and gotten tangled
ikutsu mono kiseki no ito
in so many miraculous threads
tsunagatte karamatte tadoritsuita yo
it all starts here and now
hajimeru no wa ima kono basho kara
it'll clear up after the rain, become that cloud
ame nochi hare ano kumo ni nare
and swim towards the present
ima wo oyoi de yuku
toss away the hesitation
sono kokoro shibaritsuketeru
that clings to your heart
tamerai furihodoite
you and I held hands
kimi to boku nigirishimeta
and deep inside
futatsu no te no naka de
is the eternal proof of you
kieru koto nai kimi no akashi
with our liberated hands
jiyuu na sono ryoute de
let's start again, from here
koko kara mata hajimeyou
Next Episode
I might have been the only one who considered us friends.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
But it can't be helped...
美空ひばりです。
I don't know, but...
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
I just don't want Orochimaru to take you away!
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Parting"
Parting
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
９組の皆さんによる→
I'm definitely bringing you back!
Tune in again!